Shubhechha Dey

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Eligible to Work in UK and do not require Visa sponsorship

Personal Profile

15 Inverness Mews, North Woolwich

London E16 2SP, United Kingdom

+44 07918505842

shubhechhadey1991@gmail.com

Skills

Frontend: React.js,Typescript,Javascript,Redux Saga, Graphql, Micro-frontend,Angular JS,Node Mocha,Chai,Enzyme,Jest ,Cypress,Webpack jQuery, Android, Phone gap, Appcelerator

Backend: NodeJS, SpringBoot, Elastic Search. Core Java

Devops: Git, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes

Cloud: Openshift, IBM Cloud, AWS

Monitoring tools: NewRelic, PagerDuty, Kibana

Database: MySQL, Couch DB , Mongo DB

Professional Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner IBM Cloud v1 Certified Advocate

Languages

rangaages	
English	
Hindi	
Rangali	

Professional Summary

I am a highly-motivated, conscientious, and competent senior full stack developer who spent more than 10 years within this industry. I can be relied upon to deliver everything that I set out to achieve, whilst always seeking ways to help my employer grow and save them money at the same time. With a proven track record of achievement, I can bring positivity, support and a creative mindset to any team. I pride myself on taking ownership of challenging problems, maintaining high standards, and assisting my employer in achieving their commercial objectives. With a desire and passion of continuous professional development I am confident I can add value to your organization by always ensuring your clients receive the best service possible.

Employment History

Senior Full stack developer, IBM, India

11/2015 - 08/2023

- Worked with Agile and Scrum methodologies to accomplish project milestones and meet demanding timelines.
- Implemented full stack web applications from scratch till production deployment and developed microservices
- Migrated/ Modernized 200+ legacy applications to cloud
- Tested functionality, performance and compliance of each product (both frontend and backend) against design specifications to maintain strong development standards and high customer satisfaction.
- Completed unit and regression tests on software and individual modules.
- Gathered feedback from product owners and customers throughout planning and test phases. Coaching and mentoring other developers.
- Participated in code reviews of 200 developers ensuring that all code compiled 100% coding standards and best practices
- Optimized 20 webpages for speed and performance by eliminating unnecessary scripts/styles and increasing load time by 69%

Skills: React JS, Typescript, Javascript, Redux saga, Micro-

frontends, Accessibility, Graphql, NodeJS, Apollo, Mocha, Chai, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress, Webpack, Java, Springboot, Docker, Kubernetes, Openshift, IBM

Cloud, AWS, NewRelic, Pager Duty, Kibana, MySQL, CouchDB, MongoDB, Agile Methodologies

Web and Mobile Application Developer, Cognizant Technology Solutions, India

01/2014 - 10/2015

- Consulted UX and UI designers to improve application design.
- Coordinated application plans with development teams and designed prototypes.
- Understood client application requirements and implemented accordingly to promote customer satisfaction.
- Collaborated with IT professionals, software engineers and systems analysts.
- Validated code for proper structuring, security and compatibility with different browsers, devices or operating systems.
- Troubleshoot, tested and remedied issues before software deployment.
- Developed responsive web application that works across multiple devices like desktops,tablets,phones

Skills: Android, Appcelerator, Phonegap, Angular JS, JQuery

Education

B.Tech in Information Technology, West Bengal University of Technology , India

08/2009 - 08/2013

Work Achievements

- Received "Star of the Batch" Award from Cognizant Academy during training
- Received Star Performer Award
- Received Appreciations from multiple IBM Project Managers and Scrum masters

Extra-Curricular Achievements

- Secured Best Chef Award in cooking competition in Cognizant
- Got prizes in recitation and art competitions in school
- Participated in table tennis tournaments, district, state and national level